<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>home on codenanshu learn code faster</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in home on codenanshu learn code faster</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:48:26 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Codenanshu</title>
      <link>/cloud/codenanshu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:48:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/codenanshu/</guid>
      <description>codenanshu is the this website where i am currently working on this website is my first project with HUGO and other javascript librarys , this website have huge ammount of quality content in near future this website is like a portfolio or a blog or a plateform for developer to get quality knowladge
 you can visit the website 👉 link view source code here 👉 github  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firstly</title>
      <link>/cloud/firstly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:48:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/firstly/</guid>
      <description>it is currently working phase, i am currently working on this project is this project i am going to create a social media type app where people share there post this app is like a combination of Instagram, FaceBook, Twitter and Reditt.
i am creating this app using the React Native Technology and The Firebase for the backend and Redux for state management
source code is currently hiddnen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Inspacting Js</title>
      <link>/cloud/stop-inspacting-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:47:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cloud/stop-inspacting-js/</guid>
      <description>Is it possible to remove “Inspect Element”? well yes its possible to stop inspecting the website into the browser. as you know that there are three ways to inspect a website into the browser
 using keyboard shortcuts using right click using developer menu of the browser  i have solution for the 1 and the 2 ways here is the JavaScript code but user user 3rd way is very rare cases</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy Code but Use Comments</title>
      <link>/notes/copy-code-but-use-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:46:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/copy-code-but-use-comments/</guid>
      <description>why comments are important in programming Commenting involves placing Human Readable Descriptions inside of computer programs detailing what the Code is doing. Proper use of commenting can make code maintenance much easier, as well as helping make finding bugs faster. Further, commenting is very important when writing functions that other people will use.
yes copying code is not a problem, but you know what the problem is ??. well if you not comments the documatation and why this code working or anything, there is a big problem here if you open you project after a years then are not able to understand your own code and you are unable to understand the code which you copy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Pocket to Save Pages</title>
      <link>/notes/use-pocket-to-save-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:45:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/use-pocket-to-save-pages/</guid>
      <description>pocket is already come with firefox web brower now days Pocket, previously known as Read It Later, is an application and web service for managing a reading list of articles and videos from the Internet. Released in 2007, the application was originally only for desktop and laptop computers,[2] and is now available for macOS, Windows, iOS, Android, Windows Phone, BlackBerry, Kobo eReaders, and web browsers.[3] Pocket was taken over by Mozilla, the developers of the Firefox web browser, in 2017</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Note for Future</title>
      <link>/notes/save-note-for-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 22:45:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/save-note-for-future/</guid>
      <description>as you know that we visit hundred of website in a day so we can&amp;rsquo;nt dependent on the brower history so we need to take note for our learing things like some code from stackoverflow and the website like quora or other something
the very best app to take notes is notion</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn React From Basic to Advanced</title>
      <link>/cources/learn-react-from-basic-to-advanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 07:46:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cources/learn-react-from-basic-to-advanced/</guid>
      <description>React (also known as React.js or ReactJS) is a free and open-source front-end JavaScript library for building user interfaces or UI components. It is maintained by Facebook and a community of individual developers and companies. React can be used as a base in the development of single-page or mobile applications. However, React is only concerned with state management and rendering that state to the DOM, so creating React applications usually requires the use of additional libraries for routing, as well as certain client-side functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master CSS in one article</title>
      <link>/cources/master-css-from-basic-toadvanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 07:46:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cources/master-css-from-basic-toadvanced/</guid>
      <description>Learning CSS can be a frustrating experience sometime. One of the best things about learning to code is that people who are good at coding also happen to have the skills to make games that teach other people to code.
Here are some games which help you to master CSS.
1. Flexbox Froggy This game is about Flexbox and it covers flex properties like align-items, justify-content, align-content, flex-direction, align-self, flex-wrap, flex-flow and order in 24 different levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Websites You Must Visit if You Are a Developer</title>
      <link>/tutorials/top-10-websites-you-must-visit-if-you-are-a-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 07:41:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/top-10-websites-you-must-visit-if-you-are-a-developer/</guid>
      <description>Hello World 👋
I&amp;rsquo;m Yash Waghmare, a 19-year-old 😄 tech enthusiast and a coder 👨‍💻 who is starting his journey in the field of web and software development who finally started blogging. After learning quite a bit about web development, software development, and programming languages, I thought why not give it a try to write a blog! So, I started and this is my first ever blog. Enjoy! 🥳
The Top 10 websites  1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Keyboard Shortcut in Javascript</title>
      <link>/tutorials/create-keyboard-shortcut-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 20:53:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/create-keyboard-shortcut-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Keyboard shortcuts are not only for desktop applications. You can also create shortcuts for web applications, which can come in handly in your MPA or SPA apps. Read on to find out how to create keyboard shortcuts in JavaScript.
Most applications and programs come packed with keyboard shortcuts that allow you to complete common tasks within their interfaces. Thankfully creating shortcuts within our own projects isn&amp;rsquo;t as difficult as one might think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most useful JavaScript Array Methods</title>
      <link>/tutorials/top_array_function_in_javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 22:34:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/top_array_function_in_javascript/</guid>
      <description>We underestimate what the understanding of basic array methods can do. It saves us a lot of time when building projects. At least, I feel that way, because most of the features that you build in any project boil down to manipulating the array of values.
In this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing some array methods which I&amp;rsquo;ve found most useful and must know, along with examples.
map() map() method returns a new array populated with results from calling a function provided for every element in the calling array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete JavaScript Tutorial</title>
      <link>/cources/javascript_complete_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 20:41:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cources/javascript_complete_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript is one of the most loved programming language between the prorgrammer in the world. every web developer love javascript, the most there are so many big consepts that increase the web developer productivity and help to write a good functional website.
what Is JavaScript ❓ well i think if you are a web developer then you know what javascript is. but if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what javascript is then here is the defination 👇</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 22:09:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>its codenanshu hi, my name is Anshu Meena and i am a computer science student, i am learning programming from the internet, and from my teacher. I love programming, I love to create some amazing thing in computer like a awesome website or problem solving mobile app and much more thing like machine learing and Artifical intelligence, i think any programmer love these consupts because these words sounds cool.
well thats not all about me i have many to share with, like who i am ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 22:09:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>     Submit ✉️       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>search</title>
      <link>/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 22:09:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex items-center shadow-xl w-full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;input class=&#34; bg-newgrey rounded w-full py-4 px-6 text-gray-200 leading-tight&#34; id=&#34;search-input&#34; type=&#34;text&#34; placeholder=&#34;Search&#34; name=&#34;search&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;p-4&#34; oninput=&#34;searchForData(event)&#34;&gt;
        &lt;button class=&#34;bg-neworange text-white rounded p-2 hover:bg-blue-400 focus:outline-none w-12 h-12 flex items-center justify-center&#34;&gt;
          &lt;svg xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; width=&#34;16&#34; height=&#34;16&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34; class=&#34;bi bi-search&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 16 16&#34;&gt;
          &lt;path d=&#34;M11.742 10.344a6.5 6.5 0 1 0-1.397 1.398h-.001c.03.04.062.078.098.115l3.85 3.85a1 1 0 0 0 1.415-1.414l-3.85-3.85a1.007 1.007 0 0 0-.115-.1zM12 6.5a5.5 5.5 0 1 1-11 0 5.5 5.5 0 0 1 11 0z&#34;/&gt;
          &lt;/svg&gt;
        &lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;section id=&#34;search-results&#34; class=&#34;search&#34;&gt;&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;script defer type=&#34;text/javascript&#34;&gt;
var fuse, searchInput, searchResults = null
var documents = []
const options = {
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    keys: [
      &#34;title&#34;,
      &#34;description&#34;
    ]
  };

function renderSearchResults(results){

    if (results.length &gt; 0) {

        
        if (results.length &gt; 9){
            results = results.slice(0,10)
        }

        
        searchResults.innerHTML = &#39;&#39;

        
        results.forEach(result =&gt; {
        
            
            var article = document.createElement(&#39;article&#39;)
            article.innerHTML = 
            `
            &lt;div class=&#34;searchitem&#34;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&#34;${result.item.href}&#34;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&#34;title&#34;&gt;${result.item.title}&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;p class=&#34;searchdec&#34;&gt;${result.item.description}&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;a href=&#34;${result.item.href}&#34; class=&#34;text-newgreen&#34;&gt;know more&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div&gt;
            `
            searchResults.appendChild(article)
        })

    
    } else {
        searchResults.innerHTML = &#39;&lt;p&gt;No results found.&lt;/p&gt;&#39;
    }
}
function registerSearchHandler() {

    
    searchInput.oninput = function(event) {

        
        if (searchInput.value == &#39;&#39;) {
            
            searchResults.innerHTML = &#39;&#39;
        } else {
            
            
            var query = event.target.value

            
            var results = fuse.search(`${query} *`)

            
            renderSearchResults(results)
        }
    }

    
    searchInput.focus()
    searchInput.placeholder = &#39;&#39;
}
window.onload = function() {

    
    searchInput = document.getElementById(&#39;search-input&#39;)
    searchResults = document.getElementById(&#39;search-results&#39;)

    
    fetch(&#39;/index.json&#39;, {
        method: &#39;get&#39;
    }).then(
        res =&gt; res.json()
    ).then(
        res =&gt; {

            
            fuse = new Fuse(res, options);
                res.forEach(function(doc) {
                    documents[doc.url] = {
                        &#39;title&#39;: doc.title,
                        &#39;content&#39;: doc.content,
                    }
                })

            
            registerSearchHandler()
        }
    ).catch(
        err =&gt; {
            searchResults.innerHTML = `&lt;p&gt;${err}&lt;/p&gt;`
        }
    )
}
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;search here which you want, get access to content all over the website&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchronous vs asynchronous programming and their use cases</title>
      <link>/blog/synchronous-vs-asynchronous-programming-and-their-use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:37:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/synchronous-vs-asynchronous-programming-and-their-use-cases/</guid>
      <description>Synchronous vs asynchronous programming and their use cases Synchronous and asynchronous are two different types of programming implementations that confuse a lot of new developers. This knowledge is very essential to create performant and scalable systems.
In short, a synchronous program blocks further operation till the current task execution has been completed. On the other hand, an asynchronous program allows to start multiple tasks at once, then progress and finish in overlapping time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress API for React App to Get Post</title>
      <link>/blog/wordpress-api-for-react-app-toget-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:28:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/wordpress-api-for-react-app-toget-post/</guid>
      <description>WordPress is one of the best CMS in the world but you how we can fatch WordPress API for React App to get posts to in this article i am going to provide some details for WordPress REST API for React and React Native Apps so lets take a look.
WordPress REST API WordPress have already a WP-JSON route define in PHP that help user to fetch data from the WordPress website in JSON format, The WordPress REST API provides an interface for applications to interact with your WordPress site by sending and receiving data as JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download Node JS in Ubuntu With NVM</title>
      <link>/blog/download-nodejs-in-ubuntu-with-nvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:27:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/download-nodejs-in-ubuntu-with-nvm/</guid>
      <description>one of the common problem i face is i am not able to install node JS in my Ubuntu the process is not to easy first i go to the node&amp;rsquo;s website and then install the tar package file and then type several commands to install the node js. finally i found a simple solution&amp;rsquo;s to fix this problem fast as possible Another way of installing Node.js that is particularly flexible is to use nvm, the Node Version Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to import medium post in hashnode?</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-import-medium-post-to-hashnode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:26:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-to-import-medium-post-to-hashnode/</guid>
      <description>Writers and bloggers love readers like fish love water. So when platforms like Medium.com and Svbtle launched, it was an easy way for them to publish articles, blog posts, and art-directed stories that had the immediate potential for thousands of reads just by being posted to one of those sites.
With a good story, striking images, and a little bit of luck, a single article can be catapulted into Internet fame, but at what cost?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>save your time in CSS gradients with some amazing websites</title>
      <link>/blog/css_gradient_gunrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:25:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/css_gradient_gunrator/</guid>
      <description>have you ever work with CSS gradients in your web development as you know that there are so many ways to add gradients in your website and today in this article i will provide some amazing website that help you to work better then before. so lets get started and without wasting our time lets check all website one by one
so these are the website i want to introduce to you,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Tor Browser on Ubuntu 18.04 Agreeable trick</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-install-tor-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:24:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-to-install-tor-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Tor Browser routes your web traffic through the Tor network, making it private and anonymous. When you use the Tor Browser, the connection to the website you are viewing is encrypted and protected from network surveillance and traffic analysis.
Using Tor Browser comes with few drawbacks. Browsing the web over Tor is slower than a regular Internet connection, and some major web sites block Tor users. Also, in some countries, Tor is illegal or blocked by the government-enforced firewall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradient Text In CSS</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-gradient-text-in-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:17:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-to-gradient-text-in-css/</guid>
      <description>this is really short post from me i know that YouTube started short video so i want to share short but an amazing idea with you checkout this code snippet this is you to gradient your Text In CSS
 file_type_css style.css 👇  h2 { font-size: 72px; background: -webkit-linear-gradient(blue, lightcoral); -webkit-background-clip: text; -webkit-text-fill-color: transparent; } its awesome the result of this code is look like</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolutely Best Note Taking Tool Ever Made For Programmers</title>
      <link>/blog/best-note-taking-tool-for-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:15:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/best-note-taking-tool-for-programmer/</guid>
      <description>programming is really amazing in my life but from some days i am facing some problem in my programming journey the problem is i search from my problems on the Google and get the answer but after some time i need to search again for the problem i does not able to write down my salutation in my notebook i want to note down these all the concept online so i get reference anywhere i want so finally is got question of Absolutely Best Note Taking Tool Ever Made For Programmers Made For Programmers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Programmers Love Python</title>
      <link>/blog/why-programmer-love-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:10:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/why-programmer-love-python/</guid>
      <description>Python is really amazing programming language it provide so many feature for programmers to write code and done there task fast as possible its OK but the the question is why programmers love python so here is my onions for that question . #Why Programmers Love Python
python is the language which increase there popularity day by day it increase here popularity from 2017 to 2020 but i think the compilation of python is JavaScript but that&amp;rsquo;s not our point we are here to find the answer why python love by the programmers so lt&amp;rsquo;s find out .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Programmers Love Linux</title>
      <link>/blog/why-programmer-love-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:06:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/why-programmer-love-linux/</guid>
      <description>Why Programmers Love Linux ? Linux was developed and publicly released by Linus Torvalds in 1991 September. Linux is a free and open-source operating system, unlike either macOS or Windows OS . Linux offers multiple desktop and server distro. Typically the Linux OS is employed for server and cloud software. Some popular Linux distros are Ubuntu, RedHat Enterprise Linux and Debian . Because Linux is free and open-source, it allows end-users to freely alter, utilize, distribute, and publish software code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack GitHub Contributions  With Python Programming</title>
      <link>/blog/hack-github-with-python-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 20:00:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/hack-github-with-python-programming/</guid>
      <description>GitHub is the best place for programmers, where all programmers provide there code and other programmers see the code and provide good or bad review. The problem is How To Hack GitHub Contributions whenever we have no idea to upload some codes on GitHub the GitHub leave blank our Contributions in our main profile its looks really bad that we have not contributions this days or months or sometimes years so finally i go a solution for that problem by watching some YouTube videos are waste my 30 minutes of life about searching this topic on internet and finally i got result and i am going to provide this result for you in just 5 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anime Hero - Anime finder using AWS Amplify - AWS Amplify Hackathon</title>
      <link>/blog/create-anime-finder-in-reactjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:23:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/create-anime-finder-in-reactjs/</guid>
      <description>This is really amazing project for me i don&amp;rsquo;t believe that i create this project in just 3 days actually i join hashnode in 24 February and i got notification about AWS Amplify Hackathon on 25 February i do not know any framework i have only knowledge of HTML, CSS and JavaScript so when i read the term and conditions related to hackathon then i going to learn REACT JS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>markdown syntax guide</title>
      <link>/blog/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:23:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks</title>
      <link>/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 10:55:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/thanks/</guid>
      <description>spacial thanks to these technologys and persons to there awesome code on the web which help me to develop a website like this one. the list is go on in the future, if you want your name here then please contribute to this project
thanks to Persons  CodeX Sukhpreet - &amp;ldquo;for share his projects and get some insparation&amp;rdquo; fireship.io - &amp;ldquo;get some UI recommandation&amp;rdquo; near aman - &amp;ldquo;for logo recommandation&amp;rdquo;  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
